are y'all ready for the best of the best
cold plunging is one of the most popular
Trends in the fitness Community right
now and there are a lot of benefits from
speeding up Muscle Recovery to assisting
you in combating anxiety and just
offering overall mental clarity now
unless you've been living under a rock
you know I've been busy reviewing these
cold plunges over the past year and I'm
pretty pumped to talk to you guys about
our top picks
here we go
[Music]
what's up y'all it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym and in this video I'm
gonna tell you what coal plunges made
our best list talk about some of their
features talk about the pricing and help
you decide on one of these solid options
and because I respect your time so much
I'm gonna go ahead and tell you our
number one pick for best cold plunge
it's the plunge cold plunge yep that's
right when it comes to the appearance
the materials and overall quality of a
cold plunge we definitely think the
plunge cold plunge is the best option at
the moment
now I'm going to go into further detail
on what I like about the plunge and some
of the other awards that it won on our
best list but we have a bunch of awards
like best for the money best on Amazon
and a whole lot more so definitely stick
around for the rest of the list but you
know before I get going with all that if
you're interested in reading our best
list article all you have to do is
search bar Bend best cold plunges and
you can read over all of these pics in
further detail
okay so let's get started and what would
we be doing here if we didn't kick this
video off with our number one pick now I
know I already told you our number one
pick is the plunge cold plunge but let's
expand on why it's our top pick okay so
the chiller on the side of the tub is
going to allow you to adjust the
temperature down to 39 degrees and it's
going to stay there all day long
especially with the cover it's going to
trap in that cold this is a true plug
and plunge cold plunge so all you have
to do is toss in your hose let it fill
up with water and you're good to hop
right on into it the drain also has a
hose hookup so that way you can drain
all your water without making an
absolute mess it's also going to allow
you to be less wasteful because you
don't have to use any ice whatsoever and
the filters on the side of the tub are
going to keep your water clean so that
way you know you don't have to use new
water every single time you decide to
take a cold plunge plus it's made from
acrylic so it's most likely going to
last you a lifetime now there's a
handful of options available on the
plunge website but the one that I'm
referring to right now is in fact that
base model so it's five and a half feet
long it's about two feet tall and
including your plumbing and your Chiller
it's about three and a half feet wide it
weighs 150 pounds when it's empty and up
to a thousand pounds when it's full of
water now if you do in fact want a
bigger version well there's an XL model
you can purchase also you know if you
want your water to cool off at a much
faster rate well you can opt in for that
pro version because that one's going to
feature a chiller with three times the
power as that base model now before I
get started with all the money I have to
mention you know a luxury item like
these coal plunges on this best list are
definitely subject to change now I still
think you can expect the price to be
around the same ballpark range but you
know it's definitely not a guarantee
okay so the base model of the plunge
cold plunge it's going to run you around
five grand and as you may assume you
know that XL version and the pro model
are both gonna cost you more money but
there there's also a hot and cold water
version as well and that's you know
going to cost you a little bit more
money as well now if you want to read
more about this product just search bar
bend the plunge coal plunge review and
you'll find all those fine details that
you may be looking for but since I
mentioned hot water we also ranked the
plunge as our best hot and cold plunge
option the acrylic build is going to
keep it around for essentially a
lifetime but that water is also going to
reach 103 degrees now because of this
hot water you can keep your plunge
outside during the cold winter months
and not worry about the pipes freezing
on you now I think it's pretty safe to
assume that this added feature is going
to drive the price tag up a bit so the
base model of the hot and cold cold
plunge it's going to run you around 5
500 at the moment you know considering
you do have that hot water and you're
only spending about 500 more I 100 think
it's worth that price tag
foreign
coming off our top pick the portal from
Polar monkeys makes a really strong
appearance on our best list it's pretty
affordable it's smaller than other
plunges and it can also be customized so
with that being said we gave it the
awards for best coal plunge for small
spaces best cold plunge for the money
and best customizable cold plunge why is
the portal our top pick for small spaces
well mainly because it's pretty narrow
so the tub itself is only two feet wide
and it might not even be three and a
half feet wide with the plumbing and the
chiller on the side so it's definitely
going to be able to squeeze into some
super tight spaces you also have two
different options in terms of length so
there's a four foot option and a six
foot option now six feet may be too long
for some people but you know four feet
that's pretty solid you know that's at
least a foot and a half shorter than any
of the other options either tubs excuse
me on our best list so I mean honestly
at the end of the day when it boils down
to you know just the smallest you know
tub version of a cold plunge it's hands
down the portal is running away with
that award no questions asked okay so
why is the portal also our top pick in
terms of money now the prices for these
plunges have definitely gone up recently
but you know you can get a four foot
long regular steel version of this tub
for about 2 400 bucks which is basically
half the price of the plunge and if you
want to add on hot water to your plunge
well it's gonna be around 2 900 and
that's still a really good discount from
the plunge and really all the other
options that are on the market and
honestly when you compare the price of
the portal to a hot tub it's also a
pretty good discount I mean maybe aside
from an inflatable one but you know at
the end of the day I mean overall
honestly this is a crazy deal and I
don't see any other cold plunge
companies on the market that are coming
close to this price tag now why is the
portal also our top pick for the best
customizable cold plunge well not only
is it available and four feet or six
feet long but you also have the choice
of it being black white regular steel
look or you can even get this sweet
monkey graphic that we have on the brain
pod don't worry the brain pot is on our
best list just hang tight I'll talk
about it in just a minute now honestly
this pick is a bit of a no-brainer in
our opinion because you know most other
companies aren't allowing you to have
all these customizations now some of
them might let you choose the color and
some of them might you know let you add
on some wood paneling but you're also
going to have to pay more money than
what you'd have to spend on the portal
it's also really nice that polar monkeys
is allowing you to have these
customizations on what they would
consider to be their base model so let's
summarize with the portal you know
similar to the plunge this is also a
plug and plunge cold plump so once again
just toss in your hose let it fill up
with water and you're good to go you do
have a filter on the side it's going to
keep your water clean the chiller is
going to keep your water nice and cold
where you want it to be but this Chiller
actually goes down to 36 degrees so and
I might not be that big of a deal for
some of y'all but it's definitely worth
mentioning the forefoot model weighs
about 120 pounds when it's empty and up
to 800 pounds when it's full all that
six foot model is about 140 maybe 150
pounds when it's empty and about a
thousand pounds when it's full of water
now I mentioned how you can add on hot
water with the portal this used to not
be the case you know polar monkeys used
to offer hot water with all of their
chillers all of their models you know
definitely not the case anymore but
you're still getting a solid discount
compared to the other options on the
market even if you were to add on that
hot water so if you're a little tight on
money maybe you're a little tight on
space or maybe both and you want a
designated cold plunge that can be
customized the portal is definitely your
best bet now we also have a detailed
article breaking down all the coal
plunges from Polar monkeys so you want
to read more about those fine details
just go and search bar Bend polar
monkeys whole plunge review and that
article is going to pull right up for
you
all right now let's transition to the
ice Barrel not everybody wants to spend
a couple Grand on a cold plunge and some
people just prefer that classic feeling
of water and ice so when it comes to the
best ice bath and the best cold plunge
Barrel we're rocking with the ice Barrel
the plastic material makes it super easy
to clean and it only weighs 55 pounds
when it's empty so you can easily move
it around whenever you need to it may
not be as insulated as an acrylic or
fiberglass tub but it definitely is
insulated okay so why is it our choice
for best ice bath well it's because it's
about as classic as it gets now you will
have to use a good amount of water and
you will have to use a lot of ice during
those summer months you know just to
keep that water as cold as you want it
to be but during the cold winter months
you might not have to add any ice
whatsoever so if you live in a cold area
this honestly might just be the best
choice for you in general so why is the
ice Barrel also our top pick for best
cold punch Barrel well the price is
really driving this pick right here you
know I've seen some other cold plunge
barrels out there that can be as
expensive as seven thousand dollars now
it's still going to run you around 1200
or so but that's a major discount
compared to those other options it's
also a really big discount compared to
those other options that I just broke
down for you guys so if you're looking
for a simple you know ice bath
experience a simple Barrel to just hop
on into this really is your best bet so
to sum up with the ice Barrel this is a
really convenient option for anyone
who's looking for a dedicated area to
cold plunge it doesn't take up a whole
lot of space you know it's just under
four feet tall and just under three feet
wide the plastic material makes it super
easy for you to clean and it only weighs
about 55 pounds so you can definitely
move it around your personal space
whenever you need to it does have a hose
hookup on the drain for you to drain all
that water out you do have a step stool
that's included with your purchase for
you to get in and out of the barrel the
stand is going to keep it nice nice and
sturdy and you also have a lid as well
as a cover to trap in those cold
temperatures it can hold up to 105
gallons of water but it's best to use
about 80 gallons or so and then top it
off with all of your ice now this
definitely is not a high-tech cold
plunge but it's probably your best bet
in terms of that old school ice bath
feeling we also have a detailed article
breaking down the ice barrel and all the
features everything in it has to offer
so why don't you go ahead and Google
barban ice Barrel review and that
article is going to pull right up for
you as well
[Music]
all right now let's transition over to
the brain pod so this isn't something
that I necessarily have to worry about
but for my taller people out there
watching you might have some difficulty
hopping in some of these cold plunges
however we don't really think you're
gonna have that issue with the polar
monkey's brain pod which is why we chose
it to be our best cold plunge for taller
people why is the brain pod our top pick
for any of you tall people watching well
it's because it's pretty spacious it's
about five and a half feet long it's
about three feet wide it's about two
feet tall this bad boy weighs about 140
pounds when it's empty and around 600
pounds when you fill it up with water
now the filter and the chiller are the
exact same as what you're going to find
with the portal but it's definitely more
spacious and more comfortable and just
you know overall better experience when
you're sitting in it now the cold water
version of the brainpod is going to run
you around forty five hundred dollars
but you can also add on hot water if you
want for an additional seven hundred
dollars just to sum up with the brain
pod if you're somebody who's six feet or
maybe even taller we think this is your
best bet in terms of being able to
stretch out
but also best in terms of your wallet so
there's other spacious coal plunges out
there for you to purchase but those are
going to cost you about two thousand
dollars more than what the brain pod
will it's also made from fiberglass so
it's going to be pretty durable and it
could also potentially last you a
lifetime as I mentioned with the portal
you know we broke down all of these
polar monkeys cold plunges so if you
want to read more details about what the
brain pod has to offer just go ahead and
search bar Bend polar monkey's coal
plunge review and that's going to pull
right up for you
okay up next on our list is another
option from Polar monkeys and this is
going to be the best bet for anybody who
does a lot of traveling and you want to
take your cold plunge on the road with
you but that's not really an easy task
to complete right well guess again
because Polar Monkey says just unveiled
they're brand new inflatable cold plunge
which is why it's our top choice for
best portable cold plunge okay so this
model is going to feature a durable
vinyl material real and it can come in
either four feet long or six feet long
but regardless of the length it's going
to be two feet tall and two feet wide
now you still have to Lug around your
pump your plumbing and your Chiller but
honestly I don't know if it gets any
better than this in terms of bringing
your cold plunge on the road with you
okay so the cold water version of the
inflatable plunge from Polar monkeys
it's going to run you around four grand
and if you want to have the hot water
it's gonna be about forty five hundred
dollars now this option does not include
the ozone generator which is going to
pair up with your filter and it's
designed to help keep that water clean
but you can add it on for an extra 400
bucks if you want to do so it also seems
to be pretty durable in my opinion but
polar monkeys is also going to toss in a
one year warranty if that eases your
worries in any way whatsoever so if
you're looking to travel with your coal
plunge or maybe just take it to your
buddy's house to show it off we think
the inflatable option from Polar monkeys
is hands down the best option for you to
do that
all right now my Amazon Fanatics have
been waiting for this one right here the
weigh and fly portable bathtub is our
number one choice on Amazon at the
moment it's a best seller and for good
reason it's portable and foldable but
you don't have to inflate it so it only
takes a few minutes for you to set it up
this tub only costs about 55 bucks it
only weighs about eight pounds made from
non-toxic PVC materials and the alloy
steel rings are going to keep it nice
and sturdy now it's pretty durable as
well but you still need to be careful
with it or else you could cause a tear
in the side of it and that's definitely
something that you don't want it's also
pretty compact you know it's only about
two feet tall and about three feet wide
or so so it's gonna be a great selling
point for a lot of you since you can
place it just about anywhere okay so
since this plunge has the least amount
of features there's not a whole lot to
conclude with but I really want to drive
it home to Avid Amazon Shoppers who are
looking for a cold plunge look no
further it's super small all so it's
going to be able to fit in some standing
showers and if you do in fact have a
standing shower well you can use that
hot water to fill it up setup only takes
a few minutes so it's not like you're
having to be super dedicated to it at
all times and it's also really cheap if
you're not sold on coal plunging yet and
simply want to test the waters
[Applause]
all right so now I want to spend some
time talking about the potential
benefits you could experience from cold
plunging in my opinion there's a lot but
you know I want to talk about my
personal favorites now before I do that
though I have to make sure you guys know
I'm not a doctor and this is not medical
advice so you should definitely go and
speak to a medical professional if you
do in fact want to incorporate cold
plunging into your Wellness Plan now we
all know that cold water and ice can
help you out a lot in terms of Muscle
Recovery as well as swelling but there's
more to it than that when it comes to
cold plunging so when you're hopping in
that cold water you know it's going to
activate your white blood cells which
help you fight off sickness and can in
turn help boost your overall immune
system cold plunging is also a great way
to wake up trust me you're gonna feel a
jolt of energy as you go and freeze your
butt off so if you're looking for a
great way in a fast way should I say to
wake up in the morning cold plunging may
be your solution I also personally think
that coal plunging is a great solution
for anybody who deals with anxiety on a
regular basis as you're hopping in these
cold Waters your body's going to enter
the fight or flight mode which it also
enters as you're having an anxiety
attack and you know a few sessions in a
cold plunge can actually help you learn
how to get your anxiety under control
and then we can't forget about stress so
when you're stressed your body produces
cortisol which is essentially a stress
hormone now too much cortisol is
obviously not a good thing so some
Studies have actually shown that regular
cold water exposure has actually led to
reduced stress levels which is in turn
gonna improve your overall mood
[Music]
okay so which style of coal plunge
should you buy well as you're looking to
add one of these great options off our
best list there's four different factors
that you need to think about in my
opinion the money you're able to spend
the materials you want it to be made
from your available space and then also
whether or not you want hot water if
you're working with a large budget then
you might as well go ahead and get one
of those more luxurious options from the
plunge or polar monkeys if you're
planning on plunging outside then your
best bet is going to be going after an
acrylic build from the plunge maybe this
fiberglass brain pod from Polar monkeys
or you can even make a case for the ice
Barrel because of that plastic material
and it's going to be pretty easy for you
to clean if space is your biggest issue
then you probably want to Target that
four foot long portal from Polar monkeys
but you can also make a really strong
case for the ice Barrel or the way and
fly off Amazon and if you want hot water
with your plunge well then you
definitely need to Target the plunge or
polar monkeys that's All She Wrote for
today's best list video breaking down
our favorite cold plunges regardless of
your specific needs you can't really go
wrong with any of these options I mean
that's why they're on our best list
right cold budget could be a great way
for your Muscle Recovery and don't
forget about the potential mental
benefits you may experience as well
thanks for watching everybody I hope
this video was really helpful and that I
was able to break down all of these cold
plunges and help you decide on one for
you to purchase as always stay posted
for my next video but for now head over
to barbin.com and you can read our best
list breaking down every single one of
these options in further detail just go
and search barban best cold plunges and
you can read everything that I talked
about here today I'll catch y'all next
time
foreign
[Music]